# Neima Hussain

Los Angeles, CA | huss.nei@berkeley.edu | (562) 215 6001 | LinkedIn | Github

### **SUMMARY**

A goal-oriented entry level Front-End Developer with the knowledge of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Angular, and MongoDB to develop desirable user experience across all platforms. Utilize this degree for a profession as a Front-End Engineer specializing in web and IOS development of designing and building of products.

### **EDUCATION**

### University of California, Berkeley

May 2024 | Berkeley, CA

Bachelor of Arts in Cognitive Science and Computer Science

### **SKILLS**

- Languages: Python, Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL
- Libraries: Node.js, Express, React, jQuery, Angular, Cue, MongoDB/Mongoose
- **Automation Tools:** API, JSON, Postman
- Version Control: Git, Github, VS Code
- Software: Figma, Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint

### RELATED COURSEWORK

- Structure & Interpretations of Computer Programs Discrete Mathematics Introduction to Building Apps
- Foundations of Data Science
   Full Stack Development
   Computational Models of Cognition

## **PROJECTS**

### **CubStart Berkeley**

Aug 2023 - Present | Berkeley, CA

- Designing an interactive layout, using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to generate a high-quality design.
- Developing responsive and intuitive front-end design using Flexbox.
- Collaborating with other developers, designers, and project teams to ensure successful and delivery of applications.
- Optimizing page elements to reduce loading time and debugging code to ensure cross-browser usability.

# Postman and Web Development at Berkeley

Oct 2023 | Berkeley, CA

• Built an AI Text Summarizer App whereas leverages the power of Artificial Intelligence APIs to provide concise summaries of long texts using Node.js, Express, and Postman.

# **EXPERIENCE**

### Student Tutor | Jei Learning Center, LLC.

May 2022 - Present | Cerritos, CA

- Providing help and assistance to K-12 students in Math and English.
- Conducting one-on-one tutoring sessions with students in virtual settings, focusing on various subjects.

### Frontend Developer Intern | MakeupStar Studio

Nov 2021 - May 2023 | San Jose, CA

- Developed complex user interfaces with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React to ensure optimal user experience.
- Implemented mobile responsive design using React and created mockups using Figma.
- Troubleshooted and tested web designs to ensure functionality and successful operations across all platforms.
- Designed wireframes and website mockups for desktop and mobile devices for various screen sizes.

### **Quantitative Researcher** | Cerritos College

Aug 2019 - Dec 2019 | Norwalk, CA

- Conducted a novel research study whereas performed in-depth quantitative data analysis from a theoretical perspective, including data cleaning, coding, and summary of analysis.
- Utilized statistical software to interpret results, performed technical writing, and reported data, including complex reports that
  provide statistics, demographics, and other text-based data.

### **ORGANIZATIONS**

Computer Science Undergraduate Association (CSUA) Society of Women Engineers (SWE) Cognitive Science Student Association (CSSA) UC Berkeley AI Hackathon - Cal Hacks Aug 2023 - Present | Berkeley, CA Aug 2023 - Present | Berkeley, CA Aug 2022 - Dec 2022 | Berkeley, CA Oct 2023 | Berkeley, CA

#### HONORS AND AWARDS

Dean's Honor List for Fall 2018, Spring 2019, Fall 2019, and Spring 2020